<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<schemalist>

  <schema path="/org/xrdesktop/" id="org.xrdesktop">

    <key name='event-update-rate-ms' type='i'>
      <default>20</default>
      <summary>How often XR related events should be processed</summary>
      <description>
        This affects events like polling the XR runtime for updated tracked device poses,
        determining if a controller points at an overlay, and performing window management.
        This value is also the basis for the overlay push/pull and scale functions to be fps independent.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='scroll-threshold' type='d'>
      <default>0.1</default>
      <summary>How big of a touchpad movement should generate a scroll event</summary>
      <description>
        The touchpad values range from -1.0 to 1.0 in both directions.
        Moving the finger about this value on the touchpad causes a scroll event
        to be emitted akin to a mousewheel being turned one position.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='scroll-to-push-ratio' type='d'>
      <default>2.0</default>
      <summary>How much the push/pull gesture should be amplified</summary>
      <description>
        While dragging a window, the touchpad's or thumbstick's y axis can push/pull a window away or nearer.
        This value determines how fast this happens.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='scroll-to-scale-ratio' type='d'>
      <default>0.75</default>
      <summary>How much the scale gesture should be amplified</summary>
      <description>
        While dragging a window, the touchpad's or thumbstick's x axis can scale a window's size.
        This value determines how fast this happens.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='analog-threshold' type='d'>
      <default>0.00001</default>
      <summary>Analog input below this threshold is ignored</summary>
      <description>
        A thumbstick might not rest at perfectly (0,0). This setting specifies a deadzone in which values are ignored.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='overlay-minimum-size-meter' type='d'>
      <default>0.1</default>
      <summary>The minimum size of a window</summary>
      <description>
        Windows are prevented from being scaled smaller than this value.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='overlay-maximum-size-meter' type='d'>
      <default>10.0</default>
      <summary>The maximum size of a window</summary>
      <description>
        Windows are prevented from being scaled bigger than this value.
      </description>
    </key>


    <key name='pointer-tip-resolution' type='(ii)'>
      <default>(64,64)</default>
      <summary>The pixel resolution of the pointer tip.</summary>
      <description>
        This option has no effect on the visible size of the pointer tip.
        Higher resolutions only result in improved quality.
        Note: Texture resolution will be largert than this value for being able to render animations
        without having to allocate larger textures.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='pointer-tip-apparent-width-is-constant' type='b'>
      <default>true</default>
      <summary>Whether the pointer tip should have the same apparent size, independent from the distance to the user.</summary>
      <description>
        This option disables the expected perspective of the pointer tip getting
        smaller when it is farther away.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='pointer-tip-width' type='d'>
      <default>0.05</default>
      <summary>Either the width or the apparent width of the pointer tip, depending on the pointer-tip-apparent-width-is-constant option.</summary>
      <description>
        When pointer-tip-apparent-width-is-constant is disabled, this option sets the width of the pointer tip.
        When pointer-tip-apparent-width-is-constant is enabled, this option sets the apparent width such
        that it always appears to have this width as if seen in 3 meter distance. The value of 3 meter was chosen because
        at typical usage distances, it makes the pointer tip usable both with pointer-tip-apparent-width-is-constant
        enabled and disabled.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='cursor-width' type='d'>
      <default>0.25</default>
      <summary>The width of the cursor that is copied from the desktop, respects pointer-tip-apparent-width-is-constant.</summary>
      <description>
        When pointer-tip-apparent-width-is-constant is disabled, this option sets the width of the cursor.
        When pointer-tip-apparent-width-is-constant is enabled, this option sets the apparent width such
        that it always appears to have this width as if seen in 3 meter distance.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='active-pointer-tip-color' type='(ddd)'>
      <default>(0.078,0.471,0.675)</default>
      <summary>The color of an active pointer tip e.g. pointing at an overlay</summary>
      <description>
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='pointer-tip-animation-alpha' type='d'>
      <default>0.25</default>
      <summary>The opaqueness of the pointer tip animation</summary>
      <description>
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name='inactive-pointer-tip-color' type='(ddd)'>
      <default>(1.0,1.0,1.0)</default>
      <summary>The color of an inactive pointer tip i.e. not point at anything</summary>
      <description>
      </description>
    </key>


  </schema>

</schemalist>
